{"Answer": "Global Sodium Consumption and Death from Cardiovascular Causes\n\nHigh sodium intake increases blood pressure , a risk factor for cardiovascular disease , but the effects of sodium intake on global cardiovascular mortality are uncertain .\n\nWe collected data from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary excretion and diet in persons from 66 countries ( accounting for 74.1 % of adults throughout the world ) , and we used these data to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age , sex , and country . The effects of sodium on blood pressure , according to age , race , and the presence or absence of hypertension , were calculated from data in a new meta-analysis of 107 randomized interventions , and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality , according to age , were calculated from a meta-analysis of cohorts . Cause-specific mortality was derived from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010 . Using comparative risk assessment , we estimated the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake , as compared with a reference intake of 2.0 g of sodium per day , according to age , sex , and country .\n\nIn 2010 , the estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day , and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 g per day . Globally , 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes ( 95 % uncertainty interval ( confidence interval ) , 1.10 million to 2.22 million ) were attributed to sodium intake above the reference level ; 61.9 % of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1 % occurred in women . These deaths accounted for nearly 1 of every 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes ( 9.5 % ) . Four of every 5 deaths ( 84.3 % ) occurred in low - and middle-income countries , and 2 of every 5 deaths ( 40.4 % ) were premature ( before 70 years of age ) . The rate of death from cardiovascular causes associated with sodium intake above the reference level was highest in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya .\n\nIn this modeling study , 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0 g per day . ( Funded by the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation . )\n\n", "Topic": "cardio", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "level": 0, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Sex": [], "Age": [], "Condition": [], "Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Duration": [], "Intensity": [], "Control": [], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Adverse-effects": [], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}, "Count": 1}, "Doggos_text": {"Location": "Participants were from 66 different countries", "Sample-size": "The data used accounted for 74.1% of the adults throughout the world.", "Intervention-general": "The study assessed the impact of sodium consumption.", "Outcomes-general": "The study measured death from cardiovascular causes.", "Effect-strength": "Sodium consumption was associated with 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular disease, which represent 9.5% or 1 of every 10 deaths of cardiovascular causes", "Conclusion-general": "Sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0g a day was associated with 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular diseases."}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127", "children": [{"Answer": "High blood pressure is caused by too high of sodium intake and it will increase your likelihood of developing cardiovascular disease. Most people throughout the world get about 3.95g of sodium in their diet each day. There were 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular disease in 2010. Research discovered that many of these deaths were in people who had a much greater intake of sodium than the 3.95 per day. Many of these deaths were in low and middle income countries and were premature - meaning the person died before they should have. The country that was the most affected by this was Georgia but Kenya was least affected. This is why researchers are now saying that we should do our best to keep our sodium intake to around 2g per day. Doing so is healthier for us and will help prevent us from suffering from a premature death. Research was conducted by organizations like the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.", "AssignmentId": "3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A25AJ66CYVUTBR", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NJM2BJS4XRSB16G4WY9XRU27IMCPB", "children": [{"Answer": "we collected from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary exaction and diet in persons from 66 countries, and we used these data to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age , sex , and country. we estimated the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake , as  compared with a reference intake of 2.0 g of sodium per day. In this modeling study, 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level 2.0 g per day. ", "AssignmentId": "3U4J9857OFWKVQAAUA8XMLXZQ40B7J", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A3F6TS7I3CSUM8", "Qualification": 0.46153846153846156, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3U4J9857OFWKVQAAUA8XMLXZQ40B7J", "children": [{"Answer": "One of the risk factors for high blood pressure is high sodium intake. According to a randomized study, high sodium intake was responsible for 1.65 million deaths in the world from cardiovascular causes. This accounted from nearly 1 out of every 10 deaths from this disease.", "AssignmentId": "3Q5C1WP23NM4VOEZ4K0BIP6UDVD51W", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "APHMJQQFW0U5S", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "60+", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3Q5C1WP23NM4VOEZ4K0BIP6UDVD51W", "children": [{"Answer": "1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occured in 2010 were attributed to elevated sodium consumption. ", "AssignmentId": "3WJ1OXY92B1JCUA1Y1075A9OJGCA8L", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1LMDMSKQ96PHP", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WJ1OXY92B1JCUA1Y1075A9OJGCA8L", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium intake linked to cardiovascular disease but effects are uncertain.", "AssignmentId": "38F71OA9GUHTTATD3IWIOTLA01GMF0", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A6CVN7CSC1K26", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["D"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["D"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_38F71OA9GUHTTATD3IWIOTLA01GMF0"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "Data was collected from people in 66 countries to understand sodium levels in diets around the world, and how high sodium might contribute to cardiovascular disease and related deaths. &#13;&#13;High sodium intake is responsible increasing blood pressure, and increased blood pressure can cause death from cardiovascular causes. 1.65 million annual deaths occur from cardiovascular causes that are attributed to high sodium intake. Men are at especially high risk to develop cardiovascular disease from high sodium intake, with 61.9% of the deaths that were studied occurring in men, and 38.1 deaths occurring in women. These deaths that were attributed to high sodium made up 9.5% of all deaths from cardiovascular causes. Deaths associated with high sodium intake occurred most often in the country of Georgia, and least in the country of Kenya. High sodium is considered to be intakes above the reference level of 2.0 g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A83OOIGU4606R", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDEQ4KXK", "children": [{"Answer": "It was uncertain if globally, high sodium increases blood pressure, which can than also lead to increased risk for cardiovascular disease.  So, the researchers in this study collected data from urine and diet from a sample size of people from 66 different countries.  The researchers found that from 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular disease that 1.10 million to 2.22 that were due to high sodium intake.  The researchers used the reference sodium level of higher than 2.0g per day to determine these findings.", "AssignmentId": "3EQHHY4HQTD1Z342M3LEPCA0FB0G5T", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AWK93GL7CJ3FK", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3EQHHY4HQTD1Z342M3LEPCA0FB0G5T", "children": [{"Answer": "Collected data on sodium intake in people from 66 countries and was used to quantify the consumption of sodium according to age, sex and country. 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above 2.0g/day", "AssignmentId": "308XBLVESJPUD9UP3O63R2OZRPSBRY", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A98E8M4QLI9RS", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_308XBLVESJPUD9UP3O63R2OZRPSBRY", "children": [{"Answer": "1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes in 2010 have been attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level of 2g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3TE3O85731T0PWUTKVDSQ9LVXK92RJ", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AON59V5VZU2AK", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3TE3O85731T0PWUTKVDSQ9LVXK92RJ", "children": [{"Answer": "high sodium intake showed cause for 1.65 million deaths from cardiac issues", "AssignmentId": "3L0KT67Y8F12RWNDS5KSPNRWY1LYSI", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A2YUCJ28XANFOX", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "High School", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3L0KT67Y8F12RWNDS5KSPNRWY1LYSI"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "Data was collected from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary excretion and diet in people from 66 countries and was used to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age, sex and country. The effects of sodium on blood pressure, according to age, race and the presence or absence of hypertension were calculated in a new meta-analysis of 107 random interventions. Cause specific mortality was derived from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. The estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95g/day and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51g/day. Globally 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes were attributed to sodium intake above the 2.0 g/day reference level; 61.9% were men and 38.1 were women. These deaths accounted for 1 of every 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes. 4 of every 5 deaths occurred in low and middle income countries and 2 out of 5 were premature before age 70. The highest death rates from cardiovascular causes associated with high sodium intake was in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.", "AssignmentId": "3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A98E8M4QLI9RS", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA82LW4Q", "children": [{"Answer": "A high intake level of sodium does increase blood pressure, which is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease. Nonetheless the effect of the amount of sodium intake a person engages in relation to global cardiovascular mortality rate is inconclusive. A study was conducted where they created a comparative risk assessment on sodium intake based on age, sex, and country. Globally, it was found that 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular diseases could be attributed to a sodium intake level above 2 grams of sodium per day.", "AssignmentId": "3VE8AYVF8NIE8LR99HMZJBKFGM4F8Y", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AJITIN95JSBAR", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3VE8AYVF8NIE8LR99HMZJBKFGM4F8Y", "children": [{"Answer": "Excessive sodium ingestion increases blood pressure. From data collected it was found 1.65 million annual deaths are caused by sodium levels being higher than 2.0 g per day, 61.9% in men 38.1% in women. These account for nearly 1 of every 10 cardiovascular caused deaths.", "AssignmentId": "39LOEL67OTQJS9BGPMLXI2VID5Y38U", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A2ELH7YDLFNJUZ", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LOEL67OTQJS9BGPMLXI2VID5Y38U", "children": [{"Answer": "In a study from 66 countries, 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above 2g/day", "AssignmentId": "3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDF1DKXG", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A98E8M4QLI9RS", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3OCHAWUVGP5F38KVI0POFNTDF1DKXG", "children": [{"Answer": "Excess sodium intake caused 1.65 million cardiovascular deaths in 2010.", "AssignmentId": "3PJUZCGDJ7157B0W6VM79FY4DY489E", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AON59V5VZU2AK", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3PJUZCGDJ7157B0W6VM79FY4DY489E"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "The risk of death from high sodium consumption is higher in low and middle-income countries such as Georgia and Kenya. The cardiovascular effects from the high sodium consumption are an increase in blood pressure which also is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease. The global study that was done in 2010 proved that the people who lived in \"poor\" countries and \"undereducated\" countries were at a higher risk for death from cardiovascular causes because they had a higher sodium intake. If these people had access to education about the consumption of foods and drinks high in sodium their total risk of death from cardiovascular causes would decrease. If they lower their sodium intake to even the reference intake of 2.0 g per day then their risk would decrease. In 2010 the mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day. That is 1.95 g over the reference intake and greatly increases a persons risk of cardiovascular disease.", "AssignmentId": "3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A329WHNJKAKTW7", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WETL7AQWUT05RSEROEU6ILRA5O530", "children": [{"Answer": "It is known that high sodium intake increases blood pressure, which is a risk factor for cardiovascular diseaese. However, the effects of sodium intake on global cardiovasular mortality are uncertain. By collecting data from 74.1% of adults throughout the world according to age, sex and country, it was determined that 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occured in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0 g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3PB5A5BD0WRGM7ILAW0BNWOW6I9G7O", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AON59V5VZU2AK", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3PB5A5BD0WRGM7ILAW0BNWOW6I9G7O", "children": [{"Answer": "A 2010 study on the risks of sodium intake, covering a large number of variables like age, race, sex, and location revealed daily sodium intake was about 3.95 g/day. During this year, at least 1.65 million deaths were attributed to sodium consumption of more than 2 g/day.", "AssignmentId": "3WOKGM4L721QW9ZZDGSADQNBPYGO0L", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AUPHYAKC58LPA", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["B", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["B"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WOKGM4L721QW9ZZDGSADQNBPYGO0L", "children": [{"Answer": "High sodium intake will increase blood pressure but the it is uncertain how sodium intake effects global cardiovascular mortality. ", "AssignmentId": "3V0Z7YWSIZLSI3BATFI2R6AYIQP2VF", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A3MT4SBSBPER68", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["D"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["D"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3V0Z7YWSIZLSI3BATFI2R6AYIQP2VF", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium intake above 2.0g/day directly raises death of cardiovascular causes", "AssignmentId": "3WMOAN2SRCIO7P03FYGMJUDWTLQNV1", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1KR3HNLXSLC10", "Qualification": 0.6153846153846154, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3WMOAN2SRCIO7P03FYGMJUDWTLQNV1"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "While high sodium increases blood pressure and is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease the effects on sodium intake on global cardiovascular mortality are unknown. Data was collected from urine and diet from people in 66 countries which accounts for 74.1% of adults throughout the world. The effects of sodium on blood pressure according to age, race and presence of hypertension were calculated from data in a new meta analysis of 107 randomized interventions and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality according to age were calculated from a meta-analysis of cohorts. Using comparative risk assessment, the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake were calculated compared with a reference intake of 2.0 g of sodium per day according to age, sex and country. In 2010 the estimated mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g a day. Globally, 1.65 million deaths were attributed to high sodium intake. 61.9% of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1% in women. 2 out of ever 5 deaths were before the age of 70. &#13;", "AssignmentId": "39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A2YUCJ28XANFOX", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "High School", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_39LNWE0K4VHWG90CDSTPI0FWS4IIUZ", "children": [{"Answer": "High amount of sodium in your diet leads to high blood pressure and risks cardiovascular disease. It was found that in 2010 2.0 grams of sodium per day was the average intake and globally 1.65 million people died per year related to cardiovascular causes. A large amount of deaths were because higher than average sodium intake with men being affected more than woman. Overall, this study was able to find that in 2010, 1.65 millions deaths for cardiovascular issues were caused by a sodium intake of over 2.0 grams per day. ", "AssignmentId": "3R2PKQ87NXTD31V34Q23RQY2GK5MI6", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A17MUXOICSH29I", "Qualification": 0.46153846153846156, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3R2PKQ87NXTD31V34Q23RQY2GK5MI6", "children": [{"Answer": "According to the results of a study conducted in 2010, high sodium intake increases blood pressure which is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease, but how sodium intake effects the death rate is still uncertain with reference to the data.", "AssignmentId": "3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKL3Y4W", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A3MT4SBSBPER68", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3CN4LGXD5Y9JPBL224OARKBQKL3Y4W", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium intake is associated with increased risk of cardiovascular death. Men and low-middle income countries are most affected.", "AssignmentId": "3TXMY6UCAF9DBD7V49DYXWKCDPSQCN", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A6CVN7CSC1K26", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3TXMY6UCAF9DBD7V49DYXWKCDPSQCN", "children": [{"Answer": "Survey results on sodium intake and cardiac issues, were evaluated.", "AssignmentId": "3J88R45B2HJGEZHBVSUWB4FC9C8XPL", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AHYXP6QIMYJLD", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3J88R45B2HJGEZHBVSUWB4FC9C8XPL"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "High blood pressure is a risk factor for cardiovascular diseases and eating high sodium foods increases blood pressure, but its effect on global cardiovascular mortality is uncertain.&#13;A data collected from 66 countries on sodium intake was used to quantify global consumption of sodium by age, sex and country. &#13;Globally 1.65 million annual deaths from cardiovascular causes were attributed to high sodium intake. The gender difference was 61.9% men and 38.1% women and they were 9.5% of deaths from cardiovascular diseases. 4 of every 5 deaths occurred in low and middle income countries, and 2 of every 5 deaths were premature (before the age 70). The rate of death caused by cardiovascular causes resulted from high sodium intake was highest in country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.&#13;According to this modeling study, in 2010, a total of 1.65 million deaths were attributed to high sodium consumption (above reference level 2.0g per day).", "AssignmentId": "3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AISNLDPD2DFEG", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "9.5 %": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "9.5 %": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3F0BG9B9MQ8G8Y3L42MHUWV0ACOY7O", "children": [{"Answer": "Sodium consumption in various countries was studied and assessed. Race, age, and sex was also taken into account. Sodium intake above 2.0 g per day seems to be connected to increased risk of death due to cardiovascular causes, but the link has not been officially established. Men were more likely to die when consuming sodium levels advice 2.0g. Not all counties showed equal mortality rates linked to sodium despite having similar levels in their diets.", "AssignmentId": "3LO69W1SU4YF1S7NEQ1L616X12RGLA", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A6CVN7CSC1K26", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3LO69W1SU4YF1S7NEQ1L616X12RGLA", "children": [{"Answer": "High sodium levels make your blood pressure rise. A study was done on the effects of sodium on people all across the board. All ages, races and genders. The goal was to study the death rate. The researchers found a link between sodium levels and cardiac issues.", "AssignmentId": "3B1NLC6UG0H5SDML6IUSNIFH6LHPGO", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AHYXP6QIMYJLD", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3B1NLC6UG0H5SDML6IUSNIFH6LHPGO", "children": [{"Answer": "Consuming more than 2.0g of sodium a day is attributed to 1.65 million annual deaths, accounting for 1 of every 10 cardiovascular death.", "AssignmentId": "3NKQQ8O39ZQF8YKQLESER3ZJ1ACDUH", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1KR3HNLXSLC10", "Qualification": 0.6153846153846154, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"], "1 of every 10": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"], "1 of every 10": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3NKQQ8O39ZQF8YKQLESER3ZJ1ACDUH", "children": [{"Answer": "In 2010 there were 1.65 million deaths from causes due to sodium.", "AssignmentId": "3QUO65DNQV96CVBFBN6U2XBI5PSOU0", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1AZV2XOQK7RSW", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3QUO65DNQV96CVBFBN6U2XBI5PSOU0"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "A global study was done on whether high sodium intake, which increases blood pressure is a risk factor for cardiovascular disease and deaths associated with that.  They collected data accounting for 74.1% of adults throughout the world.  They then randomly selected 107 people and then broke it down by age, sex and country.  The study indicated that average global consumption was 3.95 grams per day but these levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 per day, by various regions.  What the study found was that 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption was above the 2.0 grams per day.  This study was founded by the bill and Melinda Gates Foundation.  It was interesting to note that the highest levels of death from sodium intake was highest in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.  So as you can see, sodium intake varied greatly by regions.  ", "AssignmentId": "3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AAN06KVDS2XRY", "Qualification": 0.9230769230769231, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "60+", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KV0LJBBH36QW0YMUDWC5IZT3FBRM0", "children": [{"Answer": "In research analysis of studies conducted of 74.1% adults worldwide, researchers quantified the global consumption of sodium according to age, sex and country to determine the effects of sodium intake on the global cardiovascular mortality rate.  Analysis showed that of the globally 1.65M annual deaths from cardiovascular causes, 1.1M were attributed to sodium intake above the average consumption of 3.95g per day, with the highest correlation in the country of Georgia and lowest in Kenya.  ", "AssignmentId": "3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA94M4W4", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A35F1LYW2ZXWLT", "Qualification": 0.7692307692307693, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "24-39", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"]}, "Fine": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3ON104KXQLHF06Q2N36M6NQA94M4W4", "children": [{"Answer": "This study was on the effects of sodium intake on global mortality. Data was surveyed according to age, sex, and country. The levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 g per day and showed also the effect it has on the cardiovascular system.", "AssignmentId": "3IQ1VMJRYU5JQZTB3T6L564Z3LAA9O", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1AZV2XOQK7RSW", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "C"], "Conclusion": ["C"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["B"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["C"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3IQ1VMJRYU5JQZTB3T6L564Z3LAA9O", "children": [{"Answer": "High sodium intake increases blood pressure and cardiovascular disease; 1.65 million deaths were attributed to high sodium consumption.", "AssignmentId": "3KJYX6QCMAWSOZ9I00OUQNWFK2UVJG", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A3D8ZG1VV5FO35", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3KJYX6QCMAWSOZ9I00OUQNWFK2UVJG", "children": [{"Answer": "1.65 mill. cardiovascular deaths in 2010 were caused by high sodium intake.", "AssignmentId": "38F5OAUN5OXUM3DWU2IT8W0XLU07HG", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A2ELH7YDLFNJUZ", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "male", "Age": "24-39", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["B", "A"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_38F5OAUN5OXUM3DWU2IT8W0XLU07HG"}]}]}]}]}, {"Answer": "High sodium intake increases blood pressure but the effects of sodium on cardiovascular mortality are uncertain. &#13;&#13;The effects of sodium on blood pressure, according to demographics and the presence or absence of hypertension were calculated from a new meta-analysis and the effects of blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality were calculated. We estimated the cardiovascular effects of current sodium intake according to demographics. &#13;&#13;In 2010, the mean level of global sodium consumption was 3.95 g per day and regional mean levels ranged from 2.18 to 5.51 g per day. Globally, 1.65 million annual deaths were attributed to high sodium intake; 61.9% of these deaths occurred in men and 38.1% in women. These deaths accounted for nearly 1 of 10 deaths from cardiovascular causes. 4 of 5 deaths occurred in low and middle-income countries, and 2 of 5 deaths were premature. The rate of death associated with sodium intake above the reference level was highest in Georgia and lowest in Kenya. &#13;&#13;In this study, 1.65 million deaths from were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level.", "AssignmentId": "3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1CUPUT2GVV8CU", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 0, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "15-24", "level": 1, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "A"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["A"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3I7DHKZYGOLVL387BJFW7RAOEWE5FX", "children": [{"Answer": "Collected data from surveys on sodium intake as determined by urinary excretion &amp; diet in people from 66 countries &amp; used to quantify the global consumption of sodium according to age, sex &amp; country. The effects of sodium on blood pressure, according to age, race &amp; the presence or absence of hypertention were calculated in a new analysis of 107 random interventions &amp; the effects on blood pressure on cardiovascular mortality. In 2010, 1.65 million deaths from cardiovascular causes that occurred were attributed to sodium consumption over 2.0g/day", "AssignmentId": "3SNLUL3WO58Y6A8IYVQ2AG7OAHNLUA", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A98E8M4QLI9RS", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 1, "Education": "Some College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 2, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"], "66 country": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"], "66 country": ["Location"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["A", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["A"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3SNLUL3WO58Y6A8IYVQ2AG7OAHNLUA", "children": [{"Answer": "After collecting data from surveys on sodium intake in 74.1% of adults in the world, it was determined that 1.65 million deaths from cardioascular causes in 2010 were attributed to sodium consumption above a reference level of 2.0 g per day.", "AssignmentId": "3VNL7UK1XG4X65JXCFXUA7G2U9YTFU", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "AON59V5VZU2AK", "Qualification": 0.8461538461538461, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 2, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 3, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention"], "74.1 %": ["Participants"], "1.65 million": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"sodium consumption": ["Intervention-general"], "74.1 %": ["Sample-size"], "1.65 million": ["Effect-strength"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "A"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["A"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["A"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["A"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3VNL7UK1XG4X65JXCFXUA7G2U9YTFU", "children": [{"Answer": "Blood pressure is increased by the effects of sodium intake therefore increasing global cardiovascular mortality.", "AssignmentId": "3LRLIPTPERU37VC27QXAVFIFEJXKAB", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A1AZV2XOQK7RSW", "Qualification": 0.6923076923076923, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 3, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 4, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {}, "Fine": {}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "C"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["C"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3LRLIPTPERU37VC27QXAVFIFEJXKAB", "children": [{"Answer": "In 2010, high sodium intake led to 1.65 deaths from cardiovascular causes. ", "AssignmentId": "3TPWUS5F8AMIVA3HGIC4PL2Y1VZWCX", "Question": "NEJMoa1304127", "WorkerId": "A3D8ZG1VV5FO35", "Qualification": 1.0, "Topic": "cardio", "Hop": 4, "Education": "College", "Gender": "female", "Age": "40-60", "level": 5, "branch": "NEJMoa1304127", "Tagging": {"Coarse": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes"]}, "Fine": {"death from cardiovascular cause": ["Outcomes-general"]}}, "Doggos_crowd": {"Coarse": {"Participants": ["C", "C"], "Intervention": ["A"], "Outcomes": ["A", "B"], "Conclusion": ["B"]}, "Fine": {"Location": ["C"], "Sample-size": ["C"], "Intervention-general": ["A"], "Outcomes-general": ["A"], "Effect-strength": ["B"], "Conclusion-general": ["B"]}}, "id": "NEJMoa1304127_3TPWUS5F8AMIVA3HGIC4PL2Y1VZWCX"}]}]}]}]}]}